现在我们要区别对待
Now we want to make a distinction
在两种不同的测试之间，黑盒
between two different kinds of the testing, black box
还有白盒子。
and white box.
所以请记住，规范是
So remember that a specification is
函数行为的描述，
a description of the function's behavior,
所以参数的类型
so it's what the types of the parameter
返回值类型和约束
are, the return value type, and the constraints
以及它们之间的关系。
and relationships between those.
黑盒测试意味着你
Black box testing means that you're
选择这些测试用例
choosing these test cases only by looking
根据规格。
at the specification.
这就是我们到目前为止在这个例子中所做的。
And that's what we've been doing in the example so far.
所以我们进行了分区，寻找边界情况
So we partitioned and we looked for boundary cases
在max函数的乘法函数中，
in the multiply function of the max function,
只查看方法签名和文档
looking only at the method signatures and documentation
这些函数的注释，而不是查看实际方法
comments of those functions, not looking at the actual method
执行它们的机构。
body that implemented them.
相反，白盒测试，也叫玻璃盒，
In contrast, white box testing, which is also called glass box,
意思是你实际上在利用知识
means that you are actually using knowledge
功能是如何实现的
of how the function is implemented
选择你的测试用例。
to choose your test cases.
例如，如果一个实现很复杂，
So for example, if an implementation is tricky,
它在选择哪种算法
and it's selecting which algorithm
它将用于实现方法依赖于
it's going to use to implement the method depending
在输入的特性上，然后
on the features of the input, then you
应该确保您有一个触发
should make sure that you have a test case that triggers
每一种算法。
each one of those algorithms.
类似地，如果有内部缓存
Similarly, if there's an internal cache
在记住答案的实现中
inside the implementation that remembers answers
对于以前的输入，那么您应该确保
to previous inputs, then you should make sure
在测试用例中再次尝试相同的输入。
that you try the same input again in your test cases.
这两样东西通常都看不见
Both of these things would not be visible normally
在说明书中，只能看到，
in the specification, it can only be seen,
或者你只能把它们当作分区
or you can only think of using them as partitions if you
看看实施情况。
look at the implementation.
现在当你做白盒测试时，
Now when you're doing white box testing,
你还是要小心你的测试用例
you have to still be careful that your test cases don't
需要实际不需要的特定实现行为
require specific implementation behavior that isn't actually
规范要求的。
called for by the spec.
例如，如果规范只是说抛出一个异常
So for example, if the spec just says throw an exception
如果输入格式不正确，
if the input is poorly formatted,
那么你的测试不应该特别检查
then your test shouldn't check specifically
它是一个空指针异常，因为
that it's a null pointer exception just because that's
当前方法体的作用。
what the current method body does.
在这种情况下，规范更通用，
The spec is much more general in this case,
只是说有什么例外。
it just says any old exception.
所以你的测试用例同样需要
So your test case needs to likewise
为了维护实施者的自由，必须保持一般性。
be general in order to preserve the implementer's freedom.
我们还有很多话要说
We'll have a lot more to say about this
在课堂上谈规格，但是基本的想法
in the class on specs, but the basic idea
测试应该始终遵守规范。
is that tests should always respect the specification.